Name Greg Horvath
Legal: Permanent resident
Legal name: Gergely Horvath
email: linuxgreg@icloud.com

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/gergelyhorvath

Web: https://zeusz.github.io
Github: https://github.com/zeusz

BRIEF SUMMARY / MOST RECENT PROJECT WORK

I'm a member of **Oath/Yahoo Performance Engineering** team, overseeing performance of applications, utilization of servers, helping on performance tuning and new Hardware evaluation/procurements. I have **18 years IT** experience in **System Administration** and related fields, like **devops**, and **team management**. I'm also a **Red Hat Certified Engineer (on RHEL4)**.

I used to be a member of **Flurry of Yahoo Production engineering** team, managing over 6000 production servers, Hadoop/HBase clusters and applications associated with them, integrating Flurry with the Yahoo ecosystem. I used to be a member also of Brightroll Exchange Display Production Engineering team

I used to administer more than 1500 production servers with 100Billion PageViews/month of Yahoo Web Analytics in Hungary with local and with remote team members and managed ops team as well. I performed second and third level on call support (24/7 365 high-availability) for same. I also designed the BCP plan for Yahoo! Web Analytics, part of which was ensuring that servers would fail over to another server on a backup data center. I created the documentation and all the scripts to do a failover for 750 production servers and 750 servers in backup data centers.

Prior to Yahoo I worked for Takinfo Ltd. as a **System Administrator** and **Chief Systems Engineer**. This was a **highly-available environment**. I worked on the **infrastructural design** of a new **Backup Data Center for** the bank.

I started initially as a systems admin in small-scale environment managing 70-80 workstations and 3 Linux/Novell/Mars servers in 2001.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

08/2018 -

Verizon Media / Oath

Senior Performance Engineer

Performance in >100K servers scale regarding:

- New hardware evaluation / procurement
- performance analysis, tuning (<u>Intel Vtune</u>, <u>perf</u>, <u>iperf</u>, <u>nuttcp</u>)
- server utilization (custom tools built on top of OpenTSDB)
- serverpark refreshment and retirement
- tool automation (<u>ansible</u>, <u>PIG</u>, <u>screwdriver</u>)

The most recent projects I work(ed) on as a Sr. Performance Engineer

- Migrated our corporate scale utilization monitoring tool from a manual approach to a fully automated Apache Oozie workflow and <u>PIG</u>, overseeing >100K baremetal server utilization
- Building CI/CD pipeline for the same tool above for it's UI, mysql database and backend parts based on <u>ansible</u> and <u>screwdriver</u>
- Improved server utilization numbers all across the different properties of the company
- Some new hardware certification for large scale use (mostly 25G NIC cards)

 Building an automated framework with ansible to deliver OS level configurations to all our Lab hosts in an automated way, also to cover security patches and upgrades. (300 servers)

10/2016-08/2018

Yahoo! / Oath

Senior Production Engineer / Flurry from Yahoo

- Operating thousands of servers of Flurry mobile analytics platform including Hadoop/HBase
- CD/CI automation improvements, based on tools like Jenkins, Screwdriver, Ansible
- Yahoo Developer Network maintenance
- Flurry Web Services / Apache Traffic Server / Nginx / Java applications
- Maintaining Splunk for various applications of Flurry

The most recent projects I worked on as a Sr. Production Engineer (SRE/devops) at Flurry

- I migrated over Flurry Splunk from standalone splunk indexer configuration to cluster base scaled configuration with more indexers speeding up search, impacting all the developers work across Flurry being able to see logs from their stack to help their work and satisfy their needs, and introduced splunk log collection to all components of the production environment
- Successfully migrated over Flurry <u>Nginx</u> entry points from property owned hosts to a centralized <u>ATS</u> edge layer
- Fixed centrally managed iptables security filter mechanism to fit into Flurry's ansible configuration management
- Patched ansible with ansible playbooks and code change to customize logging mechanism with timestamps for <u>ansible pull</u>, <u>reference ansible feature request</u>

11/2015- 10/2016

Yahoo!

Senior Production Engineer, Brightroll Exchange Display

- Operating thousands of servers for native advertising platform
- CD/CI automation improvements
- Huge performance improvements, lead on Production Engineering side as a project, 5x scaled

07/2011- 11/2015

Yahoo!

Service Engineer Mgr. for Yahoo! Web Analytics - based in Hungary and last 9 month in the US

- scaled up YWA to become the primary analytical tool for the whole company from 150 production servers to 1500 within 2 years. Scaling up covers:
 - hired multiple team members
 - extended team to manage 4 team members based in California, US, 3 team members in India, 3 team members in Budapest
 - leaded automation programs / projects like CD/CI, BCP, data quality prevention for YWA
 - succeeded on technical and managerial challenges
- Trained on mgmt. by Leadership is a choice program by Sheppard Partners -http://sheppardpartners.com/
- experience with Agile teams
- experience in DevOps culture, Scrum, Kanban
- Yahoo! Superstar Team Award Yahoo! Web Analytics Team

08/2008-07/2011

Yahoo!

Service Engineer @ Yahoo! Web Analytics (formerly Indextools) - based in Hungary

- administered more than 150 RHEL4 based production servers for Yahoo! Web Analytics
 Production Environment: programming Bash, Perl scripts for BCP operations, trainer of other
 operations team members, designed whole Analytics environments
- Design of BCP plan for Yahoo! Web Analytics. The plan includes the 4 type of servers we have to failover to another server located in a backup data center. The plan includes failover processes per server or per full co-location. Also I created the documentation and all the scripts to do a failover. (for 150 production servers and 150 servers in backup data centers)

- Being responsible for all the production servers. I did second and third level on call support (24/7 365 high-availability) for first level support system engineers/operators divided up one more people in my team. I designed architectural changes and installed new production units depending on the development phases and introduced them to the first level operators. I created documentations for the production operations.
- Installed and maintained various Web servers based on Apache, Tomcat and IIS software, investigated performance issues, and managed SSL certificates.
- Designed and built Apache Web clusters for customers, designed load balancing with high availability based on Akamai and Round-robin DNS technology.
- Performed of database administration of Oracle 10, MySQL and Postgres SQL servers.
- Set-up of 24x7 monitoring of all corporate servers with email alerts using Nagios technology, two in the production data centers and two in backup data centers (data centers worldwide)
- Solved performance problems of customer's production environment including network, application and OS performance issues, developed and implemented solutions to achieve the maximum performance.
- Sorted various security issues, installed updates on Linux systems, performed full upgrades of RHEL Linux OS.
- Wrote various shell scripts for customers for tasks automation.
- Created and maintained technical documentation and production operation runbooks.
- Installed, maintained and managed SVN servers, implemented backup strategy, provided user support.
- Yahoo! Superstar Team Award Yahoo! Web Analytics Team

06/2007-08/2008

Takinfo Ltd

Chief System Engineer - based in Hungary

- Installed and configured NFS and Samba server clusters based on Red Hat Cluster Suite, deployed Automount system and provided connectivity between UNIX and Windows boxes. This cluster was the main communication gateway between the many banking applications.
- Implemented companywide LDAP authorization, developed management tool using PHP.
 Translated PAM rpm packages to Hungarian to the authentication are more suitable for the Hungarian customers.
- Installed Common Criteria requirements and recommendations for improved security for banking systems on about 60 Linux servers based on NIST evaluations.
- Installed and configured Linux boxes as various types of servers and desktops, installed security fixes.
- Maintained and configured HP-UX on Itanium platform for Progress Database (now Openedge) as a test environment. This test was for our migration plans, to choose a solution for long time, going to Itanium based servers from Alpha platform or going to x86 64 based platform with Linux.
- Installed HP EVA 4000 and 6000 SAN hardware, configured LUN based on customer's
 requirements. Created RAID groups, LUNs, configured LUN security based on WWN. Installed
 and configured HBAs on Linux, configured loop and fabric optic connections. Created high
 availability cluster solution based on HP Service Guard.
- Diagnosed and fixed hardware problems on on-going basis.
- Migrating from OpenLDAP based authentication to Red Hat Enterprise Directory Server, tuning RHEDS for 8000 employee of customers.
- Infrastructural design of the new Backup Data Center, installation of spare servers, installation of the applications as a mirror of the production environments, solving problems in BCP, like mirroring the LDAP based authentication
- Support for system administrators in 24x7/365

12/2004-06/2007

Takinfo Ltd.

System administrator – Progress Databases - based in Hungary

- Installed many Progress databases
- Design Progress databases maintenance environment for 60 customers (little Hungarian banks Savings Co-operatives, and some big one). This environment is based on shell scripts; every

- customer had a self environment. The environment includes more than 150 complicated scripts for maintenance, tuning, backup, monitoring etc...
- Provided technical support for 100+ employees. Installed and configured FreeBSD boxes as Internet servers and routers, developed and implemented firewall rules, applied security fixes.
- Help in maintenance of RHEL Linux OS for Unix system administrators
- Support for the operators in 24x7/365 for Progress database, work in 2 shifts

03/2001-12/2004

Semmelweis University Transplantation and Surgery Clinic, Budapest, Hungary System administrator

- I managed a local network within 70-80 workstations and 3 Linux/Novell/Mars servers. I managed the full installation process too.
- The servers are to work as network gateway, mail server, Web Server, file server, SQL-server, DNS server, ftp server. I made a program in MySQL/PHP for surgery registry, within the oldest database tables from the older clipper program too.
- Deployed corporate DNS servers (Bind). Managed some DNS zones.
- Provided technical supported 150+ employees.

SUMMARY OF EXPERIENCES

- Management experience with remote team members
- Agile experience
- DevOps cultural influence
- Administration of UNIX systems including user management, back-ups, software and hardware installation and configuration
- Conceptual troubleshooting and problem-solving skills
- Broad 27x7 UNIX administrator support experience
- Deep knowledge of firewall, VPN, network and security-related technologies
- Large scale environment maintenance, automation
- Able to develop and maintain scripts, programs and processes to make the administration of a rapidly growing company efficiently and effective.

PREDOMINANT SKILLS

- Innovative conceptual ability to develop
- Proficient capability to control and manage any systems effectively
- Remarkable ability to communicate the intricacies of the technical world to laymen

MANAGEMENT EXPERIENCE

- Managing SRE/Devops/Production engineering team with 3 local, 4+3 remote located team members (international, Hungary/US/India)
- Representing team to several multiple partner teams all across Yahoo (customers, stakeholders etc)
- Collaborating close with developer teams locally and remotely
- Project planning and ownership
- Coaching team members for growth, including developing plans
- Moving team from startup approach and mindset to corporate
- Transferring developer and SRE teams from waterfall towards Agile culture, Scrum and later Kanban method with customizations
- Good documentation and architecture skills
- Elaborating goals and delegating tasks in an efficient way to the team and close organizations (including partner teams)
- Removing obstacles efficiently
- Hiring and extending teams to support growth
- HW Capex management
- Efficient decision making and project management (evaluate and launch)

SOFTWARE/HARDWARE EXPERIENCE

Operating Systems

- UNIX: HP-UX, FreeBSD, IBM AIX 4.1, Tru64 UNIX, Linux: RHEL 3-4-5-6, SUSE, Debian, Ubuntu, ManDrake
- MS Windows: NT3.51-4.0, 2000 Server, 2000 Advanced Server, 2003 Server
- Other: Novell Netware 4.10/4.11/6, BeOS

Hardware

- HP, Compaq, Dell, IBM and other i386-based hardware
- SAN: HP EVA 4000/6000
- Data Center Administration of over 150 systems

Software and Development

Current:

- Apache / ATS / Nginx / HaProxy
- Postfix: install, configure
- OpenSSH
- DHCP server with dynamic DNS update
- NFS management
- TCP/IP debugging
- UNIX security (iptables)
- Extensive Bourne Shell scripting
- Perl
- Go
- Python
- Apache Pig
- Intel VTune
- Hadoop/HBase/Kafka maintenance
- Ansible/Chef/ScrewDriver/Jenkins

Older experience:

- DNS: Installation, maintenance, configure new domains
- Oracle 8-10 (Linux platform): install, configure, tuning, maintenance
- MySQL install, configure, tuning, maintenance
- ProFTP, WU-FTP
- Squid 2.x proxy
- LDAP directory server, Red Hat Directory Server, Windows 2000/2003 Active Directory
- Nagios, Grafana, proprietary monitoring systems based on OpenTSD
- HTML, PHP
- Openstack
- Splunk
- · Jenkins, Screwdriver
- SaaS environments

Collaboration softwares

Bugzilla, Siebel, JIRA, JIVE, CVS, SVN, GIT, Slack, irc, email, email list, IM

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATION

Dennis Gabor College, Hungary - Bachelor's degree, IT Engineer

In addition:

2013: Leadership is a choice program by Sheppard Partners - http://sheppardpartners.com/

2005: Red Hat Certified Engineer (RHEL 4) Certificate Number: 804005476617518

2005: Progress Administrator I-II. Certificate (Online Zrt. - Progress Hungarian distributor)

HOBBY

photography, riding bicycle to the office, reading, travelling